Contact

kangmin.xie@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kangmin-xie (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Java

Python

MySQL

Languages

Chinese (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional)

Certifications

Programming Foundations: Design Patterns

Advanced Java Programming

Honors-Awards

Joseph W. Bouknight Teaching Award

Outstanding Student Scholarship

Soccer Championship

Graduate Fellowship

Publications

Platinum-Ruthenium Bimetallic Clusters on Graphite: A Comparison of Vapor Deposition and Electroless Deposition Methods

Understanding the Growth, Chemical Activity, and Cluster–Support Interactions for Pt–Re Bimetallic Clusters on TiO2(110)

Structural features and catalytic performance in CO preferential oxidation of CuO-CeO2 supported on multi-walled carbon nanotubes

Understanding Active Sites in the Water-gas Shift Reaction for Pt-Re Catalysts on Titania

Preferential oxidation of CO in a H2rich stream over multi-walled carbon nanotubes confined Ru catalysts

Kangmin Xie

Technical Business Analyst at Indeed.com | Software Developer Austin, Texas

Summary

Experienced in full-stack web application development under Java Spring & React Framework, familiar with multiple SQL/NoSQL databases, skilled in big data analytics in Amazon Web Services, with a master degree in Information Technology from Carnegie Mellon University - School of Computer Science.

- Languages: Java*, Python*, JavaScript (TypeScript), SQL, Bash, JSP, C#, C++
- Frameworks: Spring, Spring Boot, J2EE, undertow, React & Redux, Node.js, Django
- Databases & Big Data: MySQL, HBase, MongoDB, Redis, Hadoop, Spark
- Cloud Tools: AWS (EMR, Lambda, ELB, RDS, DynamoDB#),
 Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform

Experience

Indeed.com
Technical Business Analyst
November 2018 - Present

Austin, Texas Area

As a full-stack software developer, I help people get the right jobs:

- Develop backend RESTful services using Java Spring Framework along with MySQL, Redis databases
- Develop interactive frontend with React & Redux, JavaScript & TypeScript
- Maintain automation tests using Python Selenium web driver
- Build and deploy products in Jenkins pipeline and support internal teams
- DevTools: GitLab, Jira, Datadog, Ant, Gradle, AWS (RDS, S3), Docker

University of South Carolina
Graduate Research and Teaching Assistant
August 2011 - December 2016 (5 years 5 months)

Columbia, South Carolina Area

Education

Carnegie Mellon University

Master of Science - MS, Information Technology · (2017 - 2018)

University of South Carolina

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Physical Chemistry · (2011 - 2016)

University of Science and Technology of China Bachelor of Science - BS, Chemical Physics · (2007 - 2011)